in this tutorial we'll be going over
在本教程中，我们将复习
everything you need to know about
你需要知道的一切
working with gradients in inkscape now
现在在Inkscape中使用渐变
in this lesson we're going to focus on
在这一课中，我们将重点介绍
linear and Radial gradients in
线性渐变和径向渐变
particular but if you want to learn
特别，但如果你想了解
about some of the more advanced types of
关于一些更高级的类型
gradients in inkscape such as mesh
Inkscape中的渐变，如网格
gradients and conical gradients I have a
渐变和圆锥渐变我有一个
separate tutorial for that that I'll
关于这一点的单独教程，我将
have Linked In the description below so
在下面的描述中有链接，因此
to start us off here a gradient is
我们在这里开始的时候，一个梯度是
basically a transition between two or
基本上是两个或两个之间的过渡
more colors and a good example of that
更多的颜色和一个很好的例子
would be the sunset graphic in the
将是图中的日落图形
background this sky does not have a
背景这片天空没有
single color applied to it it has a
应用于它的单一颜色它有一个
gradient applied to it where it
渐变应用到它所在的位置
transitions from lavender to this Peach
从薰衣草到桃子的转变
sort of shade so let me show you how
有点阴暗，让我来教你怎么做
this can be accomplished in inkscape I'm
这可以在Inkscape中完成，我是
going to grab my rectangle tool and I'm
拿起我的矩形工具，我就
going to click and drag on the canvas to
在画布上单击并拖动以
draw a rectangle and then I'm going to
画一个矩形，然后我要
open up my fill and stroke menu by
通过以下方式打开我的填充和描边菜单
coming down here to this color stripe
来到这里，来到这条色带
and double clicking
并双击
it when I do that the fill and stroke
当我这样做的时候，填充和描边
menu will open up over here on the right
菜单会在右边的这里打开
hand side of the screen and Under The
屏幕的手侧和屏幕下方
Fill tab you'll notice we have have
填充选项卡，您会注意到我们有
these different types of fills that we
这些不同类型的填充物，我们
can apply to an object right now we have
可以应用于我们现在拥有的对象
a solid color applied to the object but
应用于对象的纯色，但
if we wanted to apply a a gradient we
如果我们想要应用a渐变，我们
can choose one of these options over
可以从以下选项中选择一个
here we have a linear gradient which
这里我们有一个线性梯度，它
follows a linear or straight path and
沿着一条线性或直线路径行驶，
then we have a radial gradient which
然后我们有一个径向梯度，它
follows a circular or round path so let
沿着一条圆形或圆形的路径，所以让
me select linear gradient and when I do
我选择线性渐变，当我选择时
that you can see that by default the
您可以看到，默认情况下
gradient that it applies starts off with
它应用的渐变开始于
the original color on the left hand side
左侧的原始颜色
and then it transitions over to
然后它过渡到
transparency on the right hand side now
现在右手边的透明度
I'm going to grab my gradient tool from
我要去拿我的渐变工具
the toolbar over here you can also
这里的工具栏您还可以
access it by pressing the letter G on
通过按字母G来访问它
your keyboard and if I click on this
你的键盘，如果我点击这个
handle you can see the color that's
把手你可以看到颜色是
applied to this part of the gradient
应用于该部分的渐变
over here in the fill and stroke menu
在此处的填充和描边菜单中
you can see the color code you can see
你可以看到你能看到的颜色代码
the hsl values and then you can see the
HSL值，然后您可以看到
colors indexed over here in the stops
在停靠点中索引的颜色
menu now if I click on the other end of
现在菜单，如果我点击另一端
this gradient you can see now I have the
这个渐变，你现在可以看到，我有
other color selected now this is the
现在选择的其他颜色这是
same color but the alpha channel is
颜色相同，但Alpha通道
brought all the way down and by the way
一路带下来，顺便说一句
if you don't have an alpha channel here
如果这里没有Alpha通道
make sure to come up here to this drop
一定要到这里来这里投放
down and choose hsl from this list now
向下并从此列表中选择HSL
I'm going to bring the opacity of this
我要把这个不透明的东西
end of the gradient all the way up so
渐变的终点一直向上，所以
I'm going to change the alpha channel to
我要将Alpha通道更改为
100 and I'll press enter and I'm going
100，我将按回车键，然后我要走了
to give this a different color so I'm
给它一种不同的颜色，所以我
going to click on this side of the
点击这一侧的
gradient to select it and I'll choose a
渐变来选择它，然后我将选择一个
different color from my color palette
与我的调色板颜色不同
down here now by the way you don't have
顺便说一句，现在在这里你没有
have to use the color palette if you
必须使用调色板，如果您
want you can change the color using the
我希望您可以使用
color wheel or the hsl
色轮或HSL
sliders and once you've chosen your
滑块和一旦您选择了您的
colors you can take these ends of the
你可以把这些末端的颜色
gradients and move them around if you'd
渐变和移动它们，如果你
like you could just click and drag them
就像你只需点击并拖动它们
like that and you can move them as if
就像这样，你可以移动它们，就像
they were any other object in fact if
事实上，它们是任何其他物体，如果
you hold the control key it'll lock it
你拿着控制键，它就会锁上它
onto 15 Dee increments so that you can
增加15个Dee增量，这样您就可以
get a perfectly straight gradient that
得到一个完美的直线渐变
either goes vertically or
要么垂直走，要么
horizontally so let me move this back
水平的，所以让我把这个移回去
over a little
多了一点
bit now if you come up here to the top
如果你站到顶端，现在就咬一口
top of the menu you can see we have some
在菜单的顶部，您可以看到我们有一些
controls in here let's say I wanted to
这里的控制，假设我想要
reverse this gradient I can click on
反转此渐变，我可以点击
that button and it flips the gradient
那个按钮，它会翻转渐变
around so that yellow is on the left
所以黄色在左边
hand side and pink is on the right and
手边和粉色在右边，
I'm going to flip it back and it gets
我要把它翻回来，它会变得
the same effect and then over here we
同样的效果，然后我们在这里
have repeat as of right now there is no
有重复，到目前为止没有
repeat applied to this gradient so the
重复应用于此渐变，以便
default is none but if I were to change
默认设置为无，但如果我要更改
this to a direct repeat you can see what
这样直接重复一下就可以看到什么了
happens here when the gradient ends it
在渐变结束时在此处发生
just starts and stops abruptly and opens
只是突然启动和停止，然后打开
up a new one and this goes
再来一个新的，然后这就是
infinitely so let me put this back and
无限的，所以让我把这个放回去
then the other option is reflected so
那么另一个选项就是这样反映出来的
I'll choose reflected and this repeats
我将选择反射，并重复此操作
the gradient as well but it just mirrors
渐变也是如此，但它只是反映了
it each time so it's a little bit of a
每次都是这样，所以这有点像
softer transition so let me set this
更柔和的过渡，让我来设置
back to none I'm going to move my stops
回到零，我要移动我的停靠点
out a little bit and let's say I wanted
有点出局，假设我想要
to add a new color to this gradient to
将新颜色添加到此渐变以
do that all I have to do is doubleclick
这样做我所要做的就是双击
anywhere on the path with the gradient
路径上具有渐变的任何位置
tool so I'll double click right here and
工具，所以我将在这里双击并
it'll add a new stop to that gradient
它将为该坡度添加一个新停靠点
and if you look over here in your stops
如果你在站台上看着这里
index you can see all of the colors that
索引，您可以看到所有的颜色
are included in this gradient and we now
都包含在这个渐变中，我们现在
have that one in the middle that was
中间的那个是
just added and if you click on that one
刚刚添加了，如果你点击那个
to select it you can change the color of
要选择它，您可以更改
that as well so I'll make this something
也是这样，所以我要把这个做成一些东西
radically different like green just to
完全不同的绿色只是为了
show you and you can see we now have a
展示给你看，你可以看到我们现在有一个
gradient that transitions from pink to
从粉色过渡到的渐变
Green to yellow and I could take these
从绿色到黄色，我可以把这些
stops and move them around as needed and
停止并根据需要移动它们，并
this works infinitely you can keep
这是无限有效的，你可以保留
adding new stops in here if you want to
如果您想要在此添加新的停靠点
to add new parts to the
将新部件添加到
gradient and if you want to remove them
渐变，如果想要移除它们
all you have to do is just press the
您所要做的就是按下
delete key so I'll press delete to
Delete键，所以我将按Delete键
delete that one I'll click on that one
删除那个，我会点击那个
to select it press delete and then I'll
要选择它，请按Delete，然后我将
do the same thing over here and then
在这里做同样的事情，然后
we're back to our original gradient and
我们回到了最初的梯度，
by the way it works the same thing over
顺便说一句，它在做同样的事情
here in this menu you can select these
在此菜单中，您可以选择以下选项
stops just by clicking on these colors
只需点击这些颜色即可停止
in the stops index and another thing you
在停止索引中，还有一件事是您
can do is if you want to offset your
如果您想要抵消您的
gradient so that one color is more
渐变，使一种颜色更多
dominant than the other you can use this
你可以使用这一点
slider up here so let's say I wanted
滑到这里，假设我想要
more pink in this gradient I could take
在这个渐变中我可以选择更多的粉色
this slider and just bring this over and
这个滑块，把这个拿过来
then it becomes more pink dominant and
然后它变得更加粉色占优势，
it works the other way in Reverse as
它以相反的方式工作，因为
well I can take the yellow slider and
好的，我可以用黄色滑块
bring that
把那个拿来
over and there you go now there's more
过去了，你走了，现在还有更多
yellow in the
黄中之黄
gradient so now let's have a look at an
渐变，现在让我们来看看一个
example of when linear gradients would
线性渐变的示例
come in handy getting back to my
回到我的生活中来很方便
original example of the sunset right now
现在的日落的原始例子
the sky just has a single color applied
天空只应用了一种颜色
to it but if I wanted to make this look
但如果我想让它看起来
more like a realistic Sunset I would
更像是现实的日落，我会
apply a linear gradient to it so I'm
对它应用线性渐变，这样我就可以
going to click on the object to select
要点击要选择的对象
it and then I'll open up my fill and
然后我会敞开我的心扉
stroke menu I'll apply a linear gradient
笔划菜单我将应用线性渐变
and I'm going to grab my gradients tool
我要拿起我的渐变工具
and I'm going to select this end of the
我将选择这一端
gradient and instead of letting this be
渐变，而不是让它
transparent I'm going to make this a
透明的我要把这件事变成
purple shade so another way that you can
紫色阴影，所以你可以用另一种方式
apply colors to your gradient is with
使用将颜色应用于您的渐变
the dropper tool so with this end of the
滴管工具的这一端
gradient selected I will press D on my
选择渐变我将在我的键盘上按D
keyboard to grab my color selector and
键盘抓取我的颜色选择器和
then I'm going to sample this color
那我就试试看这个颜色
right here just to make it that shade of
就在这里，只是为了让它变成那样的阴影
purple
紫色
and then I'll grab my gradient tool and
然后我会拿起我的渐变工具
I'll take this stop and bring this up
我要坐这一站，把这个拿上来
here and then I'll take this one and
这里，然后我要这个，然后
bring this down and again holding
把这个拿下来，然后再拿着
control on my keyboard so that it
控件，这样它就可以
remains a perfectly vertical path and
仍然是一条完全垂直的道路
there you go just like that I was able
你就像这样，我就能
to use linear gradients to make this
要使用线性渐变来实现这一点
Sunset look more
日落看起来更多
realistic now let's have a look at how
现在让我们来看看现实是如何
radial gradients work I'm going to grab
径向渐变起作用我要抓取
my circles and ellipses tool and I'll
我的圆圈和椭圆工具，我会
hold control and click and drag to
按住Ctrl键并单击并拖动以
create a circle and now I'm going to
做一个圆圈，现在我要
apply a gradient to it but instead of
对其应用渐变，但不是
using a linear gradient this time I'm
这次我使用线性渐变
going to use a radial gradient and when
将使用径向渐变以及何时使用
I click on that you can see what happens
我点击它，您可以看到发生了什么
here uh if I grab my gradient tool you
这里，呃，如果我拿起我的渐变工具
can see that this works almost the same
我可以看到这几乎是一样的工作方式
way but the only difference is that the
但唯一不同的是，
gradient is now following a round path
坡度现在正沿着一条圆形路径行驶
instead of a linear path and I could
而不是线性路径，我可以
take these handles and bring them in
拿着这些手柄，把它们拿进来
like this and if I do that you can see
像这样，如果我这样做，你可以看到
it distorts the gradient but if I want
它会扭曲渐变，但如果我想
to maintain the aspect ratio while
要在保持纵横比的同时
scaling what I would do is I would hold
攀登我会做的事情是我会坚持
the control key or control and shift
Ctrl键或Control+Shift键
rather and it scales both at the same
相反，它以相同的速度同时扩展
time time let me try that again though
时间到了，让我再试一次
since I already distorted it the key is
既然我已经把它扭曲了，关键是
that you want to hold control and shift
你想要保持控制和变速
before you click and drag so I'll hold
在你点击并拖拽之前，我会按住
control and shift and then I'll click
按住Ctrl键和Shift键，然后单击
and drag and now it scales it with the
然后拖动，现在它会随着
aspect ratio
纵横比
preserved and again this works the same
保存下来，同样，它的工作原理是一样的
way if you want to add new colors in
如果要在中添加新颜色，请使用此方法
here you could just double click the
在这里，您只需双击
path and with that node selected you can
路径，并选择该节点，您可以
click on a different color and then it
点击不同的颜色，然后它
adds that color to the
将该颜色添加到
gradient so let me undo that let me undo
渐变，让我来撤销，让我来撤销
adding the new stop to the gradient and
将新的停靠点添加到渐变和
I'm going to reverse this gradient up
我要将这个渐变向上反转
here I'm going to click on this option
在这里，我将单击此选项
that says reverse the direction of the
这意味着反转方向
gradient and I'm going to select this
渐变和我要选择这个
option in the middle and I'm going to
中间的选项，我要
bring the alpha Channel up to
将Alpha通道设置为
100 and I'll make this one white so I'll
100美元，我会把这个做白的，所以我会
bring this up to 100 as well so that
把这个也提高到100，这样就可以
it's all white and then I'll take this
全是白色的，那我就买这个了
end of the gradient and I'll move this
渐变结束，我会移动这个
up into the right like
向右转，就像
that and then I'll change the offset of
然后我将更改的偏移量
this gradient by adding more white to it
通过向其添加更多白色来实现该渐变
so I'll take this handle and bring this
所以我拿着这个把手，拿着这个
out a little
有点出局了
bit
比特
and I'll scale this out some more I'm
我会把这件事扩大一些，我是
going to hold control and shift and
保持控制和换挡，然后
scale
比例尺
up and as you can see we were able to
如你所见，我们能够
use the radial gradients to create this
使用径向渐变创建此
simulated uh I guess you can say it sort
模拟的，呃，我想你可以这么说
of looks like a sphere or like a
看起来像一个球体或像一个
three-dimensional round
三维圆
object so now let's go over an example
对象，现在让我们来看一个例子
of when radial gradients come in handy
径向渐变何时派上用场
I'm going to use radial gradients to
我将使用径向渐变来
create a vignette effect over this
在这上面创造一个小插曲效果
graphic here so let me grab my rectangle
图表在这里，让我拿出我的矩形
tool and I'll click and drag over the
工具，我将单击并拖动
graphic to draw a rectangle that covers
绘制覆盖以下内容的矩形的图形
the graphic entirely and let me get rid
完全是图形，让我去掉
of that Stroke by holding shift and
通过按住Shift键和
clicking the X and I'm going to make
点击X，我将使
this all white and now I'm going to
这一切都是白色的，现在我要
apply a radial gradient to it I'm going
对它应用径向渐变我要
to reverse the gradient so that
要反转渐变，以便
transparency is on the inside and white
透明在里面，白色
is on the outside and then I'll scale
在外面，然后我会扩大规模
the gradient down so that the boundaries
向下渐变，以便边界
of it stay or the ends of it stay within
要么留在里面，要么留在尽头
the boundary of the
的边界
image and now I'm going to add more to
现在我要添加更多内容
the I'm going to set an offset favoring
我要将偏移量设置为
the transparent side of the gradient so
渐变的透明边因此
I'll bring that up a little bit so that
我会把这个稍微提一下，这样
you can see more of the image and if I
你可以看到更多的图像，如果我
zoom out you can see what we were able
缩小你可以看到我们能够做到的
to accomplish with that there we created
为了实现这一点，我们在那里创建了
this vignette effect where it looks like
这种光晕效果看起来像是
the edges of the graphic have been
图形的边缘已被
softened and faded out so that is how
变得柔和淡出，这就是为什么
you can go about working with linear and
你可以开始使用线性和
Radial gradients in inkscape if you
Inkscape中的径向渐变如果
found this lesson useful then consider
觉得这一课很有用，然后考虑
checking out my inkscape master class
查看我的Inkscape大师课
it's a collection of over 60 videos
这是60多个视频的集合
where I go over all of the tools and
在那里我检查了所有的工具和
features in inkscape and I explain what
Inkscape中的功能，我将向您解释
they are and demonstrate how they work
它们是并演示了它们的工作方式
kind of like how I did in this video we
有点像我在这段视频中所做的
even have a private Community where you
甚至拥有一个私人社区，在那里你可以
can ask questions and get help from me
可以问我问题并得到我的帮助
anytime you want and best of all there's
任何你想要的时间，最好的是有
no monthly membership fees you just pay
你只需支付月费就可以了
$17 one time and you're in for Life I'll
一次17美元，你就终身难忘了，我会
have some information about that down
有一些相关信息
below if you want to check that out as
如果您想检查一下，请在下面作为
always thanks for
总是感谢
watching
看
o
O